And Starring Pancho Villa as Himself is a drama,
history, war film directed by Bruce Beresford.
In 1914, the Mexican revolutionary Pancho Villa invites studios to shoot his actual battles
against Porfírio Diaz army to raise funds for financing guns and ammunition.
The Mutual Film Corporation, through producer D.W.
Griffith, interests for the proposition and sends the filmmaker Frank
Thayer to negotiate a contract with Pancho Villa himself.
Pancho Villa, played by Antonio Banderas.
Frank Thayer, played by Eion Bailey.
Sam Drebben, played by Alan Arkin.
Harry Aitken, played by Jim Broadbent.
John Reed, played by Matt Day.
William Christy Cabanne, played by Michael McKean.
And Starring Pancho Villa as Himself is a 2003 American Western biographical drama television film directed
by Bruce Beresford, written by Larry Gelbart, and starring Antonio Banderas as Pancho Villa.
The cast also includes Alan Arkin, Jim Broadbent, Michael
McKean, Eion Bailey, and Alexa Davalos.
It premiered on HBO on September 7, 2003.
Executive producer Joshua D.
Maurer, who originally conceived the story and did extensive research, sold the project to HBO and then
brought on executive producer Mark Gordon and hired Gelbart to write the screenplay.
At the time of production, this was the most expensive 2-hour
television/cable film ever made, with a budget of over $30 million.
It was shot almost entirely on location in and
around San Miguel de Allende, Mexico.
The film explores themes of mexico, mexican revolution, biography, pancho villa.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.